<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE preface PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>

<preface id="pref-oVirt_Installation_Guide-Preface">
	<title>Preface</title>
	<para>
		oVirt is an open, cross-platform virtualization management system. oVirt provides a small image that runs on a host and provides virtualization services to virtual machines, and a web-based management interface that lets you manage hosts and storage, install and remove virtual machines, level resources across a large group of machines. oVirt scales from a small group of users with little need for access control and quota management, all the way up to hundreds or even thousands of hosts with robust control over grouping, permissions, and quotas.
	</para>
	<formalpara id="form-oVirt_Installation_Guide-Preface-About_PRODUCT_Administration_User_Interface">
		<title>About &PRODUCT; Administration User Interface</title>
		<para>
			&PRODUCT; Administration User Interface is a web-based management UI application for oVirt hosts, users, and virtual machines.
		</para>
	</formalpara>
	<formalpara id="form-oVirt_Installation_Guide-Preface-About_Using_the_PRODUCT_Administration_User_Interface">
		<title>About Using the &PRODUCT; Administration User Interface</title>
		<para>
			The guide is provided as online help and as html pages. It describes how to perform a developer install of &PRODUCT; and how to use the interface to manage virtual hosts, users and virtual machines.
		</para>
	</formalpara>
	<formalpara id="form-oVirt_Installation_Guide-Preface-The_PRODUCT_Documentation_Suite">
		<title>The &PRODUCT; Documentation Suite</title>
		<para>
			&PRODUCT; documentation suite provides information on installation, development of applications, and all the latest changes.
		</para>
	</formalpara>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				&PRODUCT; Release Notes - this document contains release specific information and known issues with the beta release.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Online Help - this document describes how to use the &PRODUCT; Administration User Interface.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Developer Installation Guide - this document describes how to install a developer version of &PRODUCT; correctly and quickly.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Production Installation Guide - this document describes how to install &PRODUCT; correctly and quickly. A production install of &PRODUCT; allows a user to manage physical hosts.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				&PRODUCT; Configuration Guide - this document describes how to configure &PRODUCT;
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Appliance Development Kit User&#39;s Guide - this document describes the &PRODUCT; ADK.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<formalpara id="form-oVirt_Installation_Guide-Preface-About_the_Audience">
		<title>About the Audience</title>
		<para>
			This documentation suite is intended for
		</para>
	</formalpara>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Anyone who wants to manage virtual machines! oVirt is lightweight enough to work for a developer managing, say, a single host with four virtual machines, yet robust enough for a large organization managing tens of thousands of virtual machines. Although oVirt is developed using Fedora, oVirt is not tied to a particular platform. Solaris and Windows users can use the oVirt browser interface, and in the future the oVirt Administration Interface will run across platforms as well.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Open Source Developers who are prototyping and experimenting with &PRODUCT;. Important aspects are an easy installation of the system and the ability to make changes in order to build a community of users and developers.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Users at the enterprise level: Hardware Administrators, team administrators and virtual machine users at large or small IT facilities.
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Typically, hardware administrators can use oVirt to manage thousands of Virtual Machines running on thousands of Host systems, often with complex user roles involved.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Team administrators manage user quotas, permissions, and subgroups for team hardware, Monitors physical hosts, Maintains available team virtual machines, install images/appliances
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							oVirt users create, destroy, and generally use virtual machines available to them after connecting to virtual machines from a browser interface.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<xi:include href="Common_Content/Conventions.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"></xi:include>
	<xi:include href="Feedback.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"><xi:fallback xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"><xi:include href="Common_Content/Feedback.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"></xi:include>
	</xi:fallback>
	</xi:include>
</preface>

